I felt this overwhelming emotion while I was barely conscious.
朦朧とした意識の中で
溢れてた思いだった
At the time, I didn't have a chance to sort through my feelings.
あの時の僕は
心の中を整理する余裕もなくて
It hadn't even been a day since I met her either.
先輩と出会って
一日しか経ってないのに
I...
僕は
Hey...
先輩 先輩
I...
俺 俺は
ダメ
Don't.
言っちゃダメ
Don't say it.
Please.
お願い
Why?
なんで
Why can't I say it?
なんで言ったらダメなんですか
Because...
なんでって
There's no way I could ever love you.
海人君が私の恋愛対象になるわけないじゃない
I mean, you're younger than me, you wear glasses, you're weak...
だって年下だし メガネだし 貧弱だし
You wear glasses, you daydream, you have a dirty mind,
メガネだし 妄想するし エッチだし
you always think people are talking about you, or maybe I should say you have a huge ego.
自意識過剰っていうか
Make it stop... Just... make it stop...
やめろ やめてくれ
Put an end to my haywire imagination.
これ以上 妄想すんなよ 俺
Dear Sister,
前略 姉上様
this is your humbled brother writing.
不肖の弟です
Your little brother played with fire and had it blow up in his face.
あなたの弟は忘想した挙句 見事に自爆してしまいました
I'm sorry for being so pathetic.
情けない男で すみません
I'm sorry for even being alive.
生きてて すみません
海人君 起きて 海人君
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www.Kamigami.org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 Syura 时间轴：小青
Kaito!
Wake up, Kaito!
そろそろ 起きないと 学校に遅刻しちゃうわ
You'll be late for school!
You haven't even had breakfast yet.
もう 朝食を取る時間も
I'm taking
the day off
何
What's this?
休むって
Taking the day off?
どうかしたの 海人君
Are you all right, Kaito?
Are you sick?
もしかして 体調が
Rinon!
りのん
体に異常なし
Nothing wrong with him physically?
だったら どうして
So what's going on?
Kaito! Kaito!
海人君 海人君
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
海人君
Kaito...
今日は休みます 放っておいてください
"I'm taking the day off. Please leave me alone."
Should I really leave him alone?
ね 放っておいていいのかな
そもそも どうして 口で言わずに 紙で書いて渡してきたのかしら
First of all, why did he write it down instead of telling me?
もしかして
Is it some kind of secret code?
何かの暗号だったりして
ふん 本当に面白いわ イチカは
You're fascinating, Ichika.
何か間違ってた
Did I do something wrong?
これはね イチカ
Let me explain it, Ichika...
ただのずるやすみよ
He's skipping school.
Skipping school?
ずるやすみ
つまり 霧島君には学校に行きたくない理由ができたのね
Basically, for some reason, he didn't want to go to school today.
Maybe he doesn't want to study...
勉強したくないとか
Or maybe he doesn't want to see someone.
誰かに会いたくないとか
Doesn't want to... see?
会いたくない
理由
The reason...
What happened last night?
昨日の夜 何があったの
N-Nothing at all...
な 何もないけど
あったのね
Something did.
若いっていいわね うふふふふ
Being young is great.
Please
leave
me alone
Kaito
ねえ 美桜 昨日のこと覚えてる
Hey, Mio,
do you remember anything about yesterday?
えっと 皆で映画の話をして 乾杯してトランプしてたのは覚えてるんだけど
I remember talking about the movie, having a toast, and playing cards...
I don't remember much after that.
そこから 先はあんまり
Me neither.
実は私も
I fell asleep at some point, and my head hurt when I woke up.
いつの間にか寝ちゃってたし
起きたら 頭が痛かったし
I wonder what happened.
何でだろう
おう おはよう
'Morning!
Hey, Tetsuro!
ああ 哲郎 あんた 昨日のこと 覚えてる
What do you remember about yesterday?
Not much, really.
いや 俺もあんま分かんねえんだ
Oh, right.
登校途中 檸檬先輩と会ってさ
I ran into Lemon on my way here.
柑菜にこれって
For you, Kanna.
檸檬先輩
Lemon gave you that?
What could it...
なんだろう
What?
A photo?
写真
Jesus Christ on a pogo stick, I'm not showing this to you!
ダメダメダメダメ 見ちゃダメ
なんでだよ
But I want to see it.
ダメなものはダメなの
Are you deaf?
But why? What happened? What was I doing?
何 何なの 何があったの
昨日の私
Kanna?
柑菜
はい 席に付いて
Take your seat, everyone!
朝のホームルームを始めます
Let's start with the morning classes.
Kirishima isn't feeling well, so he's staying home today.
ええ 最初に 霧島君が具合が悪いので
欠席するとの連絡がありました
海のやつ 風邪
Kai caught a cold?
He seemed just fine yesterday...
昨日は元気そうだったけど
皆も体調には十分注意してください
You should all make sure you stay healthy.
はい では出席を取ります
Now let me take attendance.
海人君
Kaito...
愛川さん
やっぱり 私の正体分かっちゃってるのかな
Maybe he found out who I really am.
海人君
Hey...
先輩
I...
俺 俺は
I know now.
きづいたんですよ
You're no human, and you're not from Earth.
先輩はこの星の人間じゃないって
B-But that's...
そ それは
This person's an alien, and she's dangerous!
この人エイリアンすよ 超ヤベっすよ
Help me, Men in Black!
助けて この星に居るメン·イン·ブラァーック
黑衣人是一套科幻喜剧电影，改编自洛厄尔·坎宁安的同名漫画作品。该片由巴里·索南菲尔德执导，并由汤米·李·琼斯及威尔·史密斯主演。
いや 助けて
No! Someone help me!
Don't kill me!
モルモットはイヤ 解剖はもっとイヤーッ
Don't dissect me!
What a dreadful thought...
なんて恐ろしいことに
But how should I explain this to him?
でも どうやって海人君に説明したらいいか
Should I just be honest with him?
正直に話したほうがいいのかな
That might not end well...
でも その時海人君は
I wonder what she's doing...
先輩 今頃
What?! Kaito confessed to you?
ええ 海人君に告白された
Yeah, last night. Out of the blue, for real.
そうなの 昨日の夜いきなり
So what did you say?
それで 返事は
もちろんNO
Of course I refused.
Man, Kai has no idea you're way out of his league.
うわ 海のやつ身の程わきまえなかったね
Yep, 'fraid so.
恐れ多いかも
というより 無謀ね
So pitiful.
Why can't I daydream about nice things?
なんで こんな不吉な妄想をしてしまうんだ 俺は
What's wrong with you?!
何なんだよ お前は
Let's go home, Mio.
美桜 帰ろっか
Oh? You're not coming with us?
あれ
行かねえの
行くってどこに
Where are you going?
To visit Kai.
お見舞い 海んとこ
Do you want to chat him up when he's sick?
具合悪いのに 行ったら迷惑でしょう
He might be hungry, you know.
腹減らしてるかもしれないぜ
貴月先輩がいるもの ちゃんとお世話してくれるわよ
Takatsuki's there. She'll take care of him.
I guess you're right.
確かに そうだよな
She seems like the type of girl who'd tend to his every need.
イチカ先輩だったら 海のことめちゃくちゃお世話してそうだよな
Leading him step-by-waist I bet.
もう 手取り 腰取り
Now then, Kaito. Let's clean you up.
はい 海人君
キレイキレイしましょうね
ありがとうございます 先輩
Thank you so much!
I'll have to be gentle here.
ここも 念入りに
Not there!
そ そこは
Let's do it from behind now.
後ろから
My god
Face me!
Mio, I just remembered some stuff I have to do. See you later.
美桜 用事思い出したから 先に帰るね
あ 柑菜
Hey, Kanna...
はは どこ行くか バレバレ
So obvious where she's going.
哲郎君はいいの
And that's okay with you?
何が
What is?
Well, this.
それで いいの
どういう意味
What do you mean?
だから 哲郎くんは
I mean... you...
これはチャンスね
This is an opportunity.
Lemon!
檸檬先輩
Let's get going.
さ 行くわよ
Where to?
行くってどこにですか
ふふ 決まってるじゃない
Do you really have to ask?
Oh, 8 mm film?
あ 八ミリ
Is that yours?
先輩のですか
I thought this might happen, so I came prepared.
こんなことがあろうかと 用意しておいたのよ
This is going to be epic.
リアルのシーンが取れそうだわ うふふふふふ
Even pathetic losers have to eat, I guess.
どんな時でも 人って腹がへるもんだよな
What was your name? Rinon?
お前 何っつったっけ
りのんだっけ
お前もなんか食う
Want to eat too?
Delivery?
宅配かな
Yes?
はい えっ
海人君
Kaito...
た 谷川
Tanigawa!
You've got it wrong!
あの 俺 違うから ちゃんと言ってないし
I didn't ask her, and she didn't say anything either!
返事も聞いてないし
だから 笑わないで
So don't laugh at me!
What are you talking about?
何言ってるの
顔赤よ
You still look feverish.
How do you feel?
まだ 具合悪いの
あ ああ いや 大丈夫 大丈夫
I'm all right. Just fine.
ちょっと 寝たら 具合よくなったし
I slept a while longer, and I'm feeling better now.
もう 全然平気だから
Really?
ホントに
Sorry. I shouldn't lie, huh?
ごめん 嘘つくのはよくないよな
実は 今日 サボったんだ
I was just skipping school today.
Lots of reasons.
ちょっといろいろあって
Thank goodness.
よかった
元気なら よかった
I'm glad you're well.
ごめん 心配かけるような真似して
Sorry to have made you worry.
謝らなくていいよ 安心できたし
It's all good. No need to apologize.
Did you come to check up on me? Thanks.
見舞いに来てくれたんだよな  ありがとう
We don't have to stand here. Come in.
ああ 立ち話もなんだから 上がって
へえ 昨日 私に告っておいて
Would you look at this? You confessed to me yesterday, but you already brought another girl into your room.
もう 別の女の子部屋に連れ込んじゃんだ
You stud, Kaito.
海人君肉食 っていうか 雑食
You stud...
ここはまずい
We can't talk here!
へ なに
Huh? Why?
ああ えっと
Uh, isn't it nice outside?
これから どっか行かない
どうしたの いきなり
What's gotten into you?
行きたいんだ
I want to go out!
Okay. Fine with me.
いいけど
じゃ 着替えてくるから ちょっと 待ってて
Gimme a second, I'll go get changed.
お待たせ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
ど どこ行く
Where are we going?
What about Karuizawa? It's been a while.
久しぶりに 軽井沢行こっか
映画のロケハン兼ねて
We could check it out for the movie.
Okay.
なんだ 出かけるのか
What? They're going outside?
I thought Kirishima was sick.
霧島君 病気じゃなかったの
This is perfect.
これは これで 好都合よ
Let's go, Snake.
さあ 行くわよ スネーク
snaKe是游戏《合金装备》的主角，《合金装备》是一款经典的战术谍报动作游戏，游戏以其独特的潜入谍报要素深受世界各地玩家的好评
Who?
誰
このまま 家に帰らず どこかに行ってしまえば
Maybe I should just leave and never come back.
でも お姉ちゃんさんに海人君のこと頼まれてるし
But Sistersis asked me to take care of him...
海人君に谷川さん
Kaito and Tanigawa?
What are they doing?
どうして
あ まさか
Oh, they wouldn't!
先輩 地球人じゃないんすよ エイリアンすよ
A girl we know isn't from Earth! She's an alien!
助けて メン·イン·ブラァーック
Save us, Men in Black!
Rinon! Can you hear me, Rinon?
りのん 聞こえる りのん
Let me jump through the quantum link!
お願い リンゲージで私をジャンプさせて
Why isn't it responding?
なんで 返事してくれないのよ もう
You Will Say It...
Episode Three
Damn!
There's quite a few people here.
け 結構混んでるね
It is a Saturday in July.
７月の土曜日だからね
Do you have any idea where to go?
どこをロケハンする
Not really. Let's just wander around.
特に 考えてないから ぶらぶらと
All right. Let's wander around.
じゃあ ぶらぶらで
It looks almost like they're on a date.
なんだか デートみたい
Sure does.
だな
But it's hard to film them with so many people around.
しかし
こう人が多いと 撮影には向かないわね
わ なんっすか それ
What's that?
Of course I came prepared.
これぐらいは 当然でしょう
Really?
当然っすか
そうよ
Really.
The sparkle of youth lasts but a moment.
青春の煌きは一瞬
You need to put a lot of work into recording that.
それをモノにするためには
あらゆる努力が必要なのよ
Uh-huh...
そういうもんっすか
What's wrong?
どうした
ううん あの 私 喉が乾いたから
I'm kinda thirsty, so I'm gonna buy a drink somewhere.
ジュース買ってくるね
I'll go with you.
あは 俺も行くよ
Do you want something, Lemon?
檸檬先輩要ります
Yes please.
お願いするわ
Where'd they go?
どこに行っちゃったのよ もう
Please come back!
ありがとうございました
Sorry this took so long.
お待たせ
Thanks for coming with me.
ごめんね 付き合ってもらって
I don't mind.
別にいいよ 俺も 喉乾いてたし
I was thirsty too.
This is good!
ああ うめえ もう一つ大きいサイズにしときゃよかったかな
I should've bought a large.
Why did Kirishima skip school?
霧島君 どうして学校休んだのかな
Isn't it obvious?
そりゃ 決まってるだろ
Takatsuki?
貴月先輩
If he skipped school, something must've happened between them.
ま 休むくらいだからな
なんか トラブルでもあったんだろう
But this is a good chance for Kanna.
けど 柑菜からすりゃチャンスだよな
You'll get hurt...
蹴られる
if you mess with someone else's love life.
人の恋路を邪魔すると
Mess with?
邪魔してるか
I'm trying to help them out.
これでも 応援してるつもりだぜ
You're getting in the way.
してるよ 邪魔
And you always hurt yourself.
哲郎君は蹴られるよ
自分に
At least I think... that it hurts for you.
それは 多分ね
痛いよ
I appreciate the thought.
お気遣いどうも
But you're overthinking this.
けど それは 美桜の思いすごし
Kanna is just a friend of mine from way back.
柑菜はガキんごろからの幼馴染
Nothing more.
それだけだよ
Wow, the scenery is amazing from here.
おう 結構 見晴らしな
Did you find some good spots?
よさそうな場所を見つかった
A few.
まあね
Happy to hear that.
良かった
Thanks, Tanigawa.
ありがとうな 谷川
For what?
何が
For not asking why I skipped school.
学校をサボった理由 聞かないでくれって
I am curious.
気になるよ
I'm curious, but...
気になる けど
If you don't want to tell me, you don't have to.
海人君が言いたくないなら 言わなくていいよ
It's about her, obviously.
先輩のおことでさ
It's not like anything really happened, though.
で 別に特別なんかあったわけじゃなくて
Ain't that the truth.
実際 何もなかったし
It's just, you know, kinda difficult to suddenly start living with someone else, especially a girl.
やっぱさ 他人の しかも 女の人といきなり一緒に暮らすってのは
いろいろと気を遣うから
She's really beautiful, isn't she?
貴月先輩 美人だものね
She's got a nice body too.
その スタイルだっていいし
But she's older than me,
けど 年上で 外国の人だから
and she's a foreigner.
We're from two different worlds.
微妙に咬み合わないところがあったり
I came to realize that.
そういうのを意識しちゃって
You're so kind...
優しいんだ
Not at all.
そうなんじゃないよ
そうなんじゃ
What am I talking about, anyway?
何言ってんだろうな 俺
海
Kai—
What?
何
Huh? Where's Lemon?
あれ 檸檬先輩は
What... are you doing?
何 してるんですか
えっ 何が 檸檬先輩
Are you talking to me?
What? Lemon?
I was careless.
迂闊 映像美を追求するあまり 隠れるのを忘れてしまったわ
I was so focused on bringing out the beauty of the scene that I forgot to hide.
What. Are. You. Filming?!
な に を 撮ってるんですか
A young girl in the heat of adolescence, about to mumble awkward lines of a confessio—
青春真っ盛りの思春期の少女から 繰り出される
青臭い告白
Don't talk nonsense!
わけ分かんないこと言わないでください
You were filming without permission!
これは盗撮ですよ 盗撮
That's a crime, you know!
立派な犯罪です
And what's up with that photo you gave me?
ってか 今朝の写真は何なんですか
How did you get a photo of me in that pose?
あんな姿隠し撮りして
What pose?
あんな姿？
Don't worry about it!
こ こっちの話で
ああ 逃げた 待ちなさい 先輩 先輩ったら
She ran!
Hold it right there!
Stop!
What?
何なんだ 一体
Where is she?
ったく どこ行ったんだが
Isn't that her?
あれって
We've been looking for you!
もう 探しましたよ
Oh, thanks.
あら ありがとう
The ice melted.
氷溶けてる
Serves you right.
自業自得です
Kanna!
あっ 柑菜
Why are you two here too?!
ど どうして美桜たちまでここにいるの
Well...
そ それは
Lemon shanghaied us and—
いや これは 檸檬先輩に協力しろって言われて それで
You came along quite eagerly.
嬉々としてついてきたくせに
It's all Lemon's fault!
ちょ それは檸檬先輩が
Don't blame me, Kanna!
違うの 柑菜 これは
覗いてたんだ ずっと
You were all stalking me the whole time...
You... idiots!
もう 皆の バカ
I know that voice.
Where did Tanigawa go?
谷川どこ行ったんだ
Sorr—
すみません
You're here?
せ 先輩
Kaito?
海人君
Why are you—
な なんで
I, uh, just...
その 私ね
have something to tell you.
ちょっと 海人君に話がね
ある っていうか その
Kaito?
海人君
ま 待って
W-Wait!
No!
嫌です
Why are you running away?
どうして逃げるの
Why are you chasing me?
なんで 追いかけてくるんですか
I have a reason!
理由があるもの
So do I!
こっちにだってあります
Where did Kai go?
どこ行ったんだ 海は
Did he go home?
帰ったのかな
How deplorable, Tanigawa.
残念だったわね 谷川さん
What are you talking about?
どういう意味ですか
What's with the laugh now?
何笑ってるんですか もう
Why would you chase me so far?
なんでここまで
What's your reason?
理由って 何なんですか
Last night...
昨日 海人君が言おうとしたことって 私について だよね
you were about to say something about me, right?
Yeah.
Please, don't.
お願い 言わないで
It would only cause trouble if others found out.
バレたら 困る
It would be terrible.
大変なことになる
Terrible?
大変なこと
Wouldn't it?
なるでしょう
Well, depending on the circumstances, I guess...
まあ 状況によっては なるかもしれませんけど
See, it would!
ほら なるんじゃない
Then I couldn't stay at your place anymore.
そうなったら 海人君の家にもいられなくなる
Not even there...
あの場所にも
You really wouldn't need to leave...
いや 別に出ていく必要は
Well, it might get a bit awkward at times...
そりゃ 多少はぎくしゃくすると思うけど
I'm sorry.
すみません そんなに困ると思ってなかったから
I didn't think I'd end up making you so uncomfortable.
Just keep this locked up inside of you.
このことは 海人君の心の中に締まっておいて
Don't tell anyone.
皆には言わないで
I wouldn't tell anyone!
は いうわけないじゃないですか
Really?
ホントに
It's embarrassing.
恥ずかしいでしょう
Embarrassing?
恥ずかしい
Of course.
決まってます
It's that embarrassing?
そんなに
I was rejected!
俺 振られたんですよ
えっ 誰に
By who?
Question.
質問 先輩は俺がどんなこと言うと思ってたんですか
What did you think I was about to say?
That's... really a secret I can't tell anyone.
だから それは
私の 人に言えない秘密を
You've got secrets?
そうなのあるんですか
Question.
質問 昨日 海人君は何を言おうとしたの
What were you about to say yesterday?
Can't tell you.
言えません
Why?
どうして
How about you tell me your secret?
先輩こそ 人に言えない秘密ってなんですか
That's not fair. You won't give me an answer.
ず ずるい 私の質問に
If you tell me, I'll tell you.
先輩が言えば
言いますよ
ホントにわからないですか（ホントにわからないの）
You really don't know?
Really?
ホントに
あ あの
Um...
That reminds me I haven't eaten a thing today.
そういえば 今日何も食べてなかった
We didn't bring up what happened yesterday and just made small talk instead.
昨日のことは お互いに触れず
僕達は たわいない話をした
We talked about our hobbies and favorite foods.
趣味とか 好きな食べ物とか
That's it.
そう 僕達はまだ
I realized that we weren't acquainted enough to talk about much else.
その程度の関係でしかないことを知って
But somehow, it lightened the mood.
なんだか 気持ちが軽くなった
Really. Don't film me without asking first.
もう 勝手に撮ったらダメ
You should get used to it!
いいじゃないですか これからたくさん撮るんですから
You're gonna be in a movie.
That's true, but still...
それはそうだけど
Please look into the camera!
はい 目線ください
Kaito, I have a question about yesterday!
あっ はい 海人君 昨日のこと以外で 質問があります
なんです 一体誰に振られたんですか
Listening.
Who rejected you?
Well, I...
それは
Who? Who?
誰 誰
I was just kidding.
嘘ですよ 嘘
No one rejected me.
振られてなんかいません
Really?
ホントに
Really.
ホントですってば
Then do you have someone you like?
じゃあ 好きな人はいないの
Well...
それは
Oh, I know! It's Tanigawa!
分かった
谷川さんでしょう
You were hanging out together all day.
今日だって一緒にいたし
No.
違います
Then Kitahara?
じゃあ 北原さん
No.
違いますって
Then is it me?
じゃ もしかして 私だったり
あ なん て
There's no way... right?
あれ
Right?
You Were Amazing.
Episode Four
Lemon, Mr. A confessed to Ms. B!
And Ms. A to Mr. B?
Ms. C is in trouble!
I have no idea who's who.
檸檬先輩 AO君がB子ちゃんに告白しました
A美ちゃんがB太君に
C子ちゃんピンチです
誰が誰だか 分からないわ